jill mcnitt-gray: Kelly. I think you could probably put up the the QR code.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Sounds great.
jill mcnitt-gray: And then that could probably help.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Can everyone see the QR code now.
Victoria Wood: Yes.
jill mcnitt-gray: Okay.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Excellent if everyone could sign in. That would be great on this Google form.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Oh.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): mean, just trying to get the link for somebody who asked for it. Real quick.
Victoria Wood: Alright. I think you guys can go ahead and get started if you'd like to.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Alright. Sounds good.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): all right. So good morning. Good afternoon, or just good day to wherever you are. Welcome. Everyone. We're going to talk today about movement exploration. My name is Kelly Sharp, and, Jill, you want to introduce yourself.
jill mcnitt-gray: I'm Jill Mc. Right.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. And I'm from Uci, and Jill is from Usc, all right. So go ahead and let's get started, and I'll be asking questions. And this is a very interactive lecture. So please be prepared to engage oneself when one feels comfortable to do so. So our agenda for today is as follows, we're going to talk about the goals and objectives of the Pop-up science project. We're going to really think about what is movement. And the 3rd part is, what is functional movement. There's something very different
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): within that. And what information is important to gather while studying movement task. And the 5th thing is, we're going to do breakout groups to determine the Imsi obstacle, course, task, and interest. And why? What? Why would? Why are we picking those obstacles? All right. So let's go ahead and move forward, and if any time you have any questions, just
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I can't see you, so just blurt it out. How about that? All right. So the next thing to think about is our research questions for this pop-up science project is, we're really
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): thinking about, how do humans navigate challenging environments? Right? So does the surface change. Does that change the force? Is that going to change the center of mass? And we're really thinking about, we'll focus on foot placement strategies relative to center of mass trajectories and determine what individuals value in their decision-making approach. The next thing is
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): really thinking about what is movement, so can somebody give me their definition of what is movement?
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Anyone have any thoughts.
Caden: A change in position over time.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, absolutely right. Anybody else want to add something else.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay, yeah. So it's a specific instance of changing position which might have a direction or a purpose right? And then the next thing to think about is, what is the difference between what is movement and what is functional movement? So you can see here. A functional movement is where there's a specific instance of changing position which might have a direction or purpose to complete a specific task.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Now, we all know, like, for example, this is actually an example of a sit to stand and a measurement called the tug, which is a timed up and go task right? So other functional movements like you can think about, how do you grab your toothbrush and brush your teeth? Right? How do you use?
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And the thing about the tug and the sit to stand is that we do this on a daily basis to get up and move right. But from a functional perspective. What does that look like? So we're really thinking about modifications that you can think about with segment, configuration, relative reaction force and load distribution. Right. So if you change a position of center of mass within this.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): you're going to change the effect of the load distribution. So we're thinking about how, what are the different types of functional movement that we can look at within our obstacle course right, and relate that to different changes in these different configurations of segments. All right. So the next thing to think about is here. We're going to talk a little bit about our data collection setup.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): So so far, we're thinking about using ipads or iphones on tripods, collecting timestamp data and 2D footage. And then the second part that we're working on is really thinking about how we can use a drone collecting overhead data. And then the 3rd part is integrating. So before I go into the 3, rd through 5th part, let's look at this video right here. And so this is actually a drone footage
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): of an athlete at, I think, is this Usc.
jill mcnitt-gray: It's Usc, so we've got portable force plates out in the track.
jill mcnitt-gray: and we have the drone just fixed position overhead collecting high speed video. But it gives a unique perspective of center mass trajectory and feet positions, right? Especially in the acceleration phase.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, so one of our goals in our team is working like, how can we take the 2D data? And then also with the drone data and integrate it with Alpha pose and deep labcut to see what information we can actually collect. And we do know that this is going to be an interesting feat in some ways, but we're excited to see how we can navigate this. And then thinking about, how do we set up a data
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): processing pipeline and then thinking about how the data input into various models that the whole group is working on as well. So this is really where we're thinking we love to think about. You know how things can you know? What are our processes? How can those processes translate to other models? So the next thing to think about is
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): objectives for our task. What information is important to gather while studying movement tasks. So, for example, center of mass, right foot position relevant relative to center of mass trajectory is also very important. And let's take a second and watch this video of these, the Us. National amputee soccer.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): It's kind of happy.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And these are expert hoppers. Right? So
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): alright.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): So that just gives you another example of how different you know. Center of mass and foot position is relative. So the next thing that we're going to talk about here is thinking, oops.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): See the video again. Sorry about that. The next thing to think about is in our obstacle course that we want to design. We want y'all to think about what are different tasks that we could use. And why would we want to use them if we're looking at foot placement relative to center of mass? But also there are 2 main key things to think about here.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): One is we want to think about this is going to be pop up right. So we don't want to be, have to build anything right? We want to use.
jill mcnitt-gray: Isn't it.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Simple objects. Right? We want to have something that is going to be also accessible. Right can be used across all different abilities. Right? Because you. And then the 3rd thing is thinking about.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): You know, what is the why? Why, what is that task? What are we going to learn from that task right? And does it relate back to something functional.
Victoria Wood: So I have a question for you, Kelly, hopping task, the expert hoppers. How do you look at like, you know? Use of tools basically when you're doing these types of tasks and measuring these like, how does that play into your analysis like using the like crutches in that video?
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. Those sister devices.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, Jill, do you want to talk about that first? st
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah, so basically.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Wheelchairs. Yeah.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah, so it's basically looking at assistive devices. Right? So how does the assistive device assist? And so we typically take a mechanical approach and start with. But what's the free body diagram? What forces are available to you, whether you're putting hands on hand rims and pushing a wheelchair or using crutches to create forces, and you can see from the variety of tasks, even in this practice drill how there is a lot of strategy in where you're putting
jill mcnitt-gray: contact points relative to the center of mass. To then perform the functional aspects of the task, whether it's
jill mcnitt-gray: and usually like, and even in the simple task that you saw on the amputee soccer. The mechanical objective is not to fall over and also play the ball in a way that we could bring out the best in your players around you. Right? So there's a lot that goes into the trade-offs. And I think in talking with
jill mcnitt-gray: a number of the different core leaders on Mc. Is hopping is a very convenient task that we look at. It has a contact and a flight phase has a lot of different mechanical objectives. And while it's relatively simple to understand, this actually brings a lot of complexities to trade-offs that individuals are making.
jill mcnitt-gray: So I would think of it, as you have a mechanical objective at the whole system level. And the question is, how do you use your reaction forces during ground contact
jill mcnitt-gray: to help you achieve the objective of the task. So it's just part of the system, right? And we've done some interesting things with putting load cells and crutches and instrumenting wheels. If we can't measure the reaction forces say, like with a force plate, we can get a sense of that interaction by doing some instrumentation on the assistant devices. So that gives us a complete free body diagram to better understand how they're coordinating force generation to do the task
jill mcnitt-gray: as they do it. I don't know, Kelly. You may want to add to about.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, yeah.
jill mcnitt-gray: Wheelchairs. Yeah.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, absolutely. So. We have used a lot of like force mats or load cells in a wheelchair like underneath the, you know, pelvis and understanding, and then also looking at the change in trajectory of stability within the trunk. Right? So it's in. So that also adds, but it's still the whole
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): person. And you look at it's not you don't have to. It's looking at the whole model right? But there are ways to collect data of what's going on within, you know, especially within a wheelchair, and then also looking at. It's tricky on the wheels right like adding load cells on the wheels. We've done a lot of that trying to figure out what's the force a lot of. I work with a collaborator where we're correct, that we're trying to create devices
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): that you're changing the load from the shoulder. So the load that is necessary from the shoulder to actually propel a wheelchair is, you know.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): 10% of what it should be. Right? So yeah, I think that's a really interesting question. And I think that we have. There's navigated it pretty well. And we look at the whole system, and it doesn't change in that way. If that makes sense.
Victoria Wood: Yeah. Great. Thank you.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. Great question. Okay, Jill, this is awesome.
jill mcnitt-gray: We're going to go to breakouts.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Oh, yeah, oh, sorry. Yeah, all right. So now, what we're gonna do is we're gonna set up different breakout groups. And what we want you to think about in these breakout groups is one we want you to identify. How about? We say you identify 2 to 3 tasks, and why, and I want you to make sure that you keep in mind right that these tasks need to be something that we can set up with little, or you know little
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): materials. If that makes sense, and also, why would you have that obstacle? What are you trying to learn from it? What's the objective? What is the learning outcome from that? And how does it really think about center of mass relevant to foot placement or relevant to whatever the task is anything else? There, Joe.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah, I think the other part, too, is you're going to be randomly assigned to different groups. And so I think some of the things I've learned from
jill mcnitt-gray: working with the different core leads in the. And there's going to be some interesting things about individuals, capacities that you could figure out like that. Sit to stand example, how someone self selects where they put their ankle relative to the knee may give you some clues of how they are taking advantage of their ratio of strengths of the knees and the hips to get out of the chair. So there may be some technical things you might be able to pick up.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think also, if we go back to some of the work loop work that we saw previously in some of our workshops is really thinking about what we can learn in terms of force, velocity, and and lengths, whether it be muscle.
jill mcnitt-gray: tendon units. And then I think this also brings up, maybe looking at different surfaces as well as how might we be strategic in the setup to learn a little bit more about what's the role of the tendon versus the muscle in the muscle tendon unit. So we're trying to keep the research questions in mind as we select these tasks and each of the levels of analysis that we have in Mc is really rich
jill mcnitt-gray: and figuring out, if we do these obstacle courses, what might we learn? And I think, in talking, especially with the core 3 group.
jill mcnitt-gray: Not only do we want to see how they do the tasks in a laboratory situation, but we want to have a better understanding of what their choices might be based on their capacities. So I bring all of that context in, because all of us are going to be looking at movement in very different levels. And we're working away from steady state motion into unsteady motion. So bring that into the conversation. I know it's
jill mcnitt-gray: take also a little bit of time to introduce yourself what you're you know where you are, what you're working on and what your interest is in this, and then we'll give you about 20 min. Check in on you at 20 min to see if you need more time, and the idea is to brainstorm what these activities might be. Talk about the why behind it, and then report back about what you're learning to the rest of the groups. So we'll ask each of you to chime in in the the next 20 min.
jill mcnitt-gray: Have fun with this.
jill mcnitt-gray: Be creative. Feel free to try out your recording devices if you need to. Don't worry about that so much right now, but we'll talk a little bit more about how we'll do the collective videos later.
jill mcnitt-gray: So have fun.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And if you have any questions you can ask them, and we can respond to them, or we can come into your breakout room. Yeah, thank you.
Victoria Wood: Before I split up the breakout rooms. Does anybody have any questions about the goals,
Victoria Wood: or objectives of the next like 20 min.
jill mcnitt-gray: Okay. Okay.
jill mcnitt-gray: Fun. Exploring.
Victoria Wood: I'm gonna make 5 breakout rooms. This is a little bit unique because we have those watch parties. If you're in a watch party if you want to, just like not, join your breakout room. And instead, just like, turn your video off and split up into breakout rooms on your own or breakout groups on your own, feel free to do that.
jill mcnitt-gray: My 2 cents. It's best to try out things.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
jill mcnitt-gray: So you might even hopefully you have your sneakers.
Victoria Wood: Yep, don't hurt yourselves, though.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah, stay within your capacity.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Exactly.
Victoria Wood: Alright! We're we're.
Emily Smith: I'm happy to join with someone else, too.
Emily Smith: Here.
Victoria Wood: Okay, each one has about 3. I think some of these have them watch parties, though.
Victoria Wood: so it might be 2 in some of these groups is that okay?
Victoria Wood: Just 2 people.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Where did Joe go?
Victoria Wood: I think. She joined one of the breakout rooms.
Victoria Wood: You're welcome to do that, too. I you got assigned to one you don't have to join. If you'd like to stay here and monitor questions.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, I was just gonna do the question thing. If that makes sense, probably one of us has to monitor questions.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Thank you so much.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, of course.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): So we can give them a 5 min warning at hmm, maybe 9, 40, or something like that.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I can't hear you.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay, I will look for questions, and then we can give them a 5 min warning at like 9 40. Does that sound good.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, that sounds great.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay, thank you so much.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, sorry. I realized I was muted, I think while you were asking me.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, it's okay. I was just like, well, I'll just give her a minute. She looks like she's deeply in thought right now.
Victoria Wood: Sorry I had people joining who needed to be assigned to.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Oh, yeah, I know.
Victoria Wood: Not realizing.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I do this with. I teach a large class of 400, and I do the breakout groups for 400, and it's just mad chaos the 1st 7 min. Right? That you're, you know, students are late. And you're like, Okay, how does this work like.
Victoria Wood: Yep.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And then I'm always sending them like I I use the quiz a lot like questions and stuff during the time period while they're in there, and
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): so like.
Victoria Wood: With this.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, but it gets a little tricky sometimes, you know. So all right. Well, thank you. I'm gonna turn my camera off real quick, and I'll be back on. I'll look for questions.
Victoria Wood: Okay, sounds good. I'll send a reminder at 1240, a 5 min reminder.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, thank you. This is fun. We'll see what they come up with.
Victoria Wood: Yeah.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): It always makes me laugh.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Well, and I'm such a different. My training is so different. So.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): But Kitten.
Victoria Wood: Do you come from a dance background right.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): No, actually, not too much. I'm a neuroscientist. But I studied Axon regeneration, but more of a cot like now I do more of like, why do we make decisions right? After brain injury.
Victoria Wood: Okay.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Hi.
Kristen Jakubowski: My breakout room. Buddy had to go run somewhere else, so could I get put into a different breakout room.
Victoria Wood: Yes, absolutely. I will move you into another one right now. Thanks.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): For reaching out awesome.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): You're like I'm alone in this breaking
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Kristen. Where are you located?
Kristen Jakubowski: I'm at Emory in Georgia, tech right now.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Oh! Nice! Great!
Kristen Jakubowski: Yeah.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I went to school in Virginia.
Victoria Wood: Okay, thanks for joining.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Good, excellent! Alright! I'll be back.
Victoria Wood: Sounds good.
Victoria Wood: Hey, Ben?
Victoria Wood: Think, did you just join, or did I just miss you earlier?
Benjamin Fargnoli: I joined. I just didn't get assigned to a breakout room.
Victoria Wood: Yes, okay, I will assign you now. So they're just in breakout rooms right now, coming up with different like dynamic tasks.
Benjamin Fargnoli: For the obstacle course right.
Victoria Wood: Yes,
Victoria Wood: Yeah, okay, let me assign you to.
Victoria Wood: So I need it.
Victoria Wood: This room.
Victoria Wood: i'm gonna assign, you to room one, because I think one of them has a a watch party. If it already has 3 people, I'll move you to a different room.
Victoria Wood: All right.
Benjamin Fargnoli: Sounds good.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Everything. Okay.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, I think so. We've had a couple people join, but I've assigned them.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And owner, James, do you want to join a great breakout group, or is he.
Victoria Wood: Had messaged me. He is the he's 1 of the watch parties.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. Okay, okay, good. Okay. Just checking to make sure.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And by the way, you're doing an awesome job. So thank you for all your hard work.
Victoria Wood: Thanks. I am. I think I'm catching up. There's a lot of.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): A lot groups, but a lot.
Victoria Wood: It's been fun. It's a great institute, lots of really cool research and things going on.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Are you new to Uci, or.
Victoria Wood: Yeah. Yeah. So I actually, I'm working remotely. From Georgia. Tech. So I'm like, part time with Mc part time with a different grant that's based in Georgia tech. So.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay.
Victoria Wood: That's it.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Excellent.
Victoria Wood: Thank you so much, of course.
Victoria Wood: Alright! I'll go ahead and send out the 5 min warning. Now.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Great
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): and Victoria. How do we get? Oh.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): how do we get the AI transcription.
Victoria Wood: So I get sent the summary at the end.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
Victoria Wood: The AI transcription.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Can you just make sure that we get the summary? Jill and I do so because it'll be hard to take notes and facilitate this conversation? I just, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Absolutely. Yeah. There is like, I get the transcription of the video. But it's usually pretty rough.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
Victoria Wood: But the summary tends to be good.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Pretty good. Yeah.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): no. And I've I've used. I use. I put the summary sometimes in chat, Gpt to clean it up, and it does a really good job.
Victoria Wood: That's smart.
Victoria Wood: I should do that, I think. Yeah, I think Monica's done that before with like using Claude. And they're like beautiful summaries at the end, and it's like I can't compete with this. I can't take.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Claude is my favorite. I write everything with Claude I mean not my papers, but like you know what I mean, like administratively.
Victoria Wood: yeah, it's very helpful if I use like the word meeting too many times in an email. And I'm just like, please help me.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, it's good.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): because I have to write so many emails to like faculty and stuff. And it just like it just summarizes it. It's great.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, the administrative load. I'm sure it's like chair. That's extreme.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Helps. And it's so funny because my mso doesn't know how to use it. And I taught her how to use it. Yesterday I was like, you need to learn how to use this. It's a great tool.
Victoria Wood: It is a great tool.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, all right, I guess we can bring them back.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
Victoria Wood: Those, all rooms.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I'm excited to hear these tasks.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): So, Victoria, we had 5 groups right.
Victoria Wood: We ended up having 4 combined to the fiscal.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay. Great. Thank you.
Victoria Wood: Everybody should join back in the next 30 seconds or so.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. Cause then it kicks them out.
Victoria Wood: Yes.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I like that tool.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I can't hear you, Kisa.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Yeah, we were the 1st to jump out of our breakout room.
Victoria Wood: Practicing dynamic movement. There I see.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Exactly
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): alright. We'll wait like 10 more seconds, and then we'll start and do some reporting out. I hope you all had fun with this?
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Alright. So does group One. Wanna report out.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): did you all designate a reporter, or does anyone.
jill mcnitt-gray: I don't even know who's Group One. So.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Huh!
jill mcnitt-gray: I think I was in Group One.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay.
jill mcnitt-gray: Want to talk.
jill mcnitt-gray: But, Victoria, you might be able to tell us if we.
Victoria Wood: I should have written that down room one, I think.
jill mcnitt-gray: Did have Jill in it. Yes, okay, alright.
jill mcnitt-gray: Lena. Would you like to talk about your balance capacity assessment with the beam walking.
Emily Smith: I know we've talked about this before, but we were just talking about our
Emily Smith: narrowing balance beam assessment in which there's 6 foot sections of beam that go from about a foot wide, and there's 4 different and widths, and it ends at about half an inch wide. It's basically standard wood sizes from Home Depot. Our particular motivation was to stratify individuals, balance capacity across a wide range of
Emily Smith: abilities and disabilities.
Emily Smith: So we've tested people with Parkinson's. It was originally.
Emily Smith: Andrew Soars tested it with prosthetic prosthesis users.
Emily Smith: And we've tested it on a variety of dancers, modern dancers, partner dancers, ballet dancers.
Emily Smith: And the reason
Emily Smith: we we control the conditions. So people cross their arms. And then what you do is report back the the distance that people
Emily Smith: get before they need to step off.
Emily Smith: And
Emily Smith: that give us one measure in which we can have a number that allows us to compare across vastly different balance abilities. And so far, typically, these
Emily Smith: clinical scales are have ceiling and floor effects.
Emily Smith: We ask people across their arms so that they're all using kind of similar strategy. And then we're not. The number doesn't depend on the strategy that they're used for how how much the arms are involved, even though it's not a very naturalistic
Emily Smith: situation, because this is an assessment and not a study of how people most effectively reverse a beam.
Emily Smith: And then we use those numbers to corroborate with
Emily Smith: other experiments that we do where we measure
Emily Smith: brain activity and muscle activity and want to know the the differences across these different abilities and and differences.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Excellent, but.
Emily Smith: Yeah. And we discussed. And and there there are instances where where we have actually studied
Emily Smith: muscle activity and some kinematics while traversing game.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Hmm.
Emily Smith: Demonstrating sort of ballet dancers, using the same strategies that they do for over bound. And other people have input
Emily Smith: explore movement. Let's say while they're they're traversing
Emily Smith: the beam. But we are quite limited. And the things that we've actually
Emily Smith: in the study of the movements while people are on the view.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Excellent. Thank you so much for sharing all right. Any other. Any discussion about a beam task?
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I love beam tests.
James Finley: Anybody have any other thoughts about a beam task? Okay? So.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Go ahead, I'll chime in. Can you all hear me? Sure? Do.
James Finley: Okay.
James Finley: this is James from the Usc group. So there are a group of about 9 of us here in a room. But we're using my laptop and don't have good video. So we also had an idea for looking at a balance beam as well as a way to vary to both challenge balance, but also potentially induce, let's say, anxiety or sort of
James Finley: I guess that's the best term where you might look at having a balance beam. That's different heights above the ground. We'd have to think about doing that in a way that is safe. But even if it's not very narrow and you raise it off the ground. That might be a way to look at how people move when
James Finley: you know when there's that sort of possibility of a large fall, even if the probability is really small.
Victoria Wood: So I actually in in my research for my Phd, we we wouldn't test like astronauts and people after like centrifuge studies. And these types of tasks
Victoria Wood: and beams would not be safe for people with like a gravity transition involved. But we would do tandem walks which would get like a very similar kind of test, but wouldn't be as like
Victoria Wood: dangerous when you have that poor of balance that might be like an easier, portable thing. But I agree that the like anxiety and like the decision-making process when there's a beam and height involved, is really interesting. There.
James Finley: Yeah, I mean, this is, this is a little bit more complicated. But people have also done this with VR, where you simulated height. So you don't have the actual risk of injury, but it generates a very similar feeling of anxiety.
jill mcnitt-gray: How? How do you scale like
jill mcnitt-gray: in the VR situation? Is there a way, to quote? Add cost or risk for accounts? Maybe in a gaming situation, or
jill mcnitt-gray: you know what I mean, like
jill mcnitt-gray: consequences of some sort that no one gets hurt.
James Finley: Yeah, so there are several different ways that you can.
James Finley: So this gets back to maybe the discussion about the objective of the task. So we can, we can in VR create an objective, whether it's gamifying it by giving you points for finishing. You know the course in a certain amount of time adding penalties when you have errors, or, let's say, Miss Foot, placements that are off a given target. So there are ways that we can construct an objective function, basically
James Finley: and penalize people based on how they perform or reward people. So that's a whole. Another discussion about how you motivate behavior. So all those things are are possible.
Emily Smith: Can I ask a question.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah.
Emily Smith: Are you measuring like skin conductance or something, when people are exposed as a measure of like stress or anxiety?
James Finley: So I had a student last year who was starting to do some of that. This is in particular to VR, but it's for
James Finley: studies we do with, similar to what you know what you all do, where we were doing perturbations during treadmill walking. So we were looking at one of the goals was to see how measures of skin conductance change in response to perturbations of different size. This was a high school intern who we had who left, and we haven't picked up the project. The nice thing is that they're pretty good skin conductance sensors. You can get that you can just interface with, like an Arduino for really really cheap.
James Finley: But that's something that I think is a really great measure of, you know. Anxiety.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Excellent. I've used the scan sensors. It just it's gotten much better. But when I 1st started using their a little messy, the data was a little convoluted. You had to have really set time periods of when you were looking for the change. All right. Another group.
Victoria Wood: There was another group with Kisa in it.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: So unfortunately, I have to run away to a meeting with our Vp. For research to find out about my funding for the next period of time. But Kristen, ilana, and Caitlin can. I took notes. I left them with Caitlin. I'm sure that they can
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: report back on what we talked about, which was really fun. So sorry. I'll I'll try and get back to the meeting as soon as I can, but I don't know if I'm gonna be out for the rest of the duration. But yeah.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: good luck.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Sending you lots of energy for that Combo.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Alright. Does someone from y'all's team wanna talk.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: I just need one second to make sense.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): No worries.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): The notes here before.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: We're talking about.
Kristen Jakubowski: I can. Yeah, I can dive in while Caitlin's reading handwriting.
Kristen Jakubowski: the one of the major things that we talked about was ways that you could sort of get at someone's capacity to do different tasks. And it came from my background as an athlete where we did a lot of ladder drills as part of training, and you could do that. We obviously bought the ladder itself, but you could also just put tape on the ground which would make it very easy to be able to do sort of anywhere you want to go.
Kristen Jakubowski: And with that, if you could basically think of a task you could do it and if you think about inter individual variability or across
Kristen Jakubowski: people who have different functional capacities, you could just do like a forward task and a backwards task where most people in their everyday lives don't have to walk backwards. And so you may see a lot of functional differences between populations in those different tasks.
Kristen Jakubowski: Caitlin, I'll see if you have any other notes in there.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: Yeah, we kind of had started talking about balance and limb asymmetry. So hopping tasks on dominant versus non-dominant legs.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: And then we had started going into, you know, like functional tasks, like stepping up on stairs successively of different heights
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: to see kind of how the the strategy changes when maybe the height of the step is increased or decreased, going upwards or downwards and etc.
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: And yeah, the latter
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: the agility ladder with the the tape on the ground, I think, is where we had
Kiisa Carla Nishikawa: kind of stopped a little bit.
jill mcnitt-gray: Can I ask a question about the ladder drills? And what
jill mcnitt-gray: about what you're learning from them, maybe, and what the value is in terms of
jill mcnitt-gray: how the that particular assessment gives insight to the other activity you're interested in with that group.
jill mcnitt-gray: So say, for example, if you're a soccer player and you're warming up with a ladder drill. You see this all the time. So what is the you know? What is the intention of doing that task in terms of the value. Add to the performance of upcoming soccer performance versus maybe as a researcher, what you might learn about the coordination strategies, balance, impulse, generation combination of trade-offs, those kind of things by doing a ladder task so explore that a little bit more for us.
Kristen Jakubowski: Yeah, I mean, I think for a soccer player it is you would see it. During warm up I played hockey, and so we did it for warm up as well.
Kristen Jakubowski: And it's
Kristen Jakubowski: in a lot of ways. The different tasks that you can do within a ladder may mimic some of the tasks that you're gonna have to do on the field.
Kristen Jakubowski: Whether it's a a quick, cutting maneuver.
Kristen Jakubowski: it also is just a way to I.
Kristen Jakubowski: Athletes get in their heads. I fully admit that this help totally happens. It's a way to like, get your feet moving fast.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah.
Kristen Jakubowski: And like, just sort of like, warm up your body, warm up brain, neuromuscular connections. And how much of that is physiological versus just in your brain, I think, is something that could be very widely explored. But I would say from like a soccer player like warm up example, that that would be where I would see it.
Kristen Jakubowski: I think, on the other side of it, as a research assessment, I think sort of similar to the narrowing beam. Walking test is.
Kristen Jakubowski: do soccer players have synergies or have coordination test strategies that are similar across the different drills that you do within the ladder, similar across the ladder versus overground walking versus you have a naive participant. Come and do it. What strategies are they doing?
Kristen Jakubowski: Another thing that we talked about is sort of this, this risk reward, or a speed accuracy. Trade off where, if you tell an athlete to do that ladder as fast as possible, and they're going to be timed, and they're going to be ranked. They're going to go and do it as fast as possible, and accuracy may diminish.
Kristen Jakubowski: If you tell someone who's naive to it their accuracy. One is probably going to be lower than an athlete's, but 2. They may rate that speed accuracy, trade off very differently, and may not perform it as quickly in order to optimize the accuracy of it.
Kristen Jakubowski: So I think that there's a lot of research questions that you could get at at motivation, at
Kristen Jakubowski: strategies, not only coordination strategies of the neuromuscular system, but also just overall the strategy of the individual by using a using a ladder, use something similar to that.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think that's those are really interesting points you brought up. So I'm gonna just throw a couple of ideas out here. Right? So I always look at
jill mcnitt-gray: warming up is kind of tuning the nervous system for what they're able to do right. But now you've added some other things of the incentive. We're going to tie you, and we're going to rank you. And you're going to give this to a bunch of competitive people. Okay, okay, just take that as a moment.
jill mcnitt-gray: and I'm motivated to get my time score up. So what's going to make my contacts better? It could have a lot to do with
jill mcnitt-gray: nothing to do with the feet so much as maybe the core stabilization. So you get more out of the ground right? And if that's part of the warm up. That's actually not a bad thing, I think, because body control is a big thing in injury prevention. If you warm that up and activate the core to get the legs moving faster. That brings up a lot of interesting things that I think translates a lot to especially high velocity gait.
jill mcnitt-gray: And this brings into the ability to do the task along with also maintaining balance, which is a big part of this performance piece, at least from what I see in the elite athlete group. So I think it's very rich. But I think what you've also done is identified. How you do the task, or where the incentives are, will may very much change how you have to do that right, and whether
jill mcnitt-gray: I don't know. So that brings up a lot of issues like, if we come up with an obstacle course, it might be the same task, but with very different incentives and or
jill mcnitt-gray: competition consequences or something. So that that's very cool, very versatile.
jill mcnitt-gray: and and adds a lot of dimensions. So thank you.
Kristen Jakubowski: Yeah, the other thing, too, just to sort of add on to that, too. We also talked about it being a a way to test personality types so similar to some of the work that Monica's done in the birds is
Kristen Jakubowski: the incentives you give, the instructions you could give could start probing different personality types as well, which we've talked about ways to be able to do that in humans. And I don't think we we've settled on a really great assessment of that yet that can really get sort of across these tasks.
jill mcnitt-gray: Great. Thank you.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Alright!
Victoria Wood: I think there was another group with Jordan and the mines watch party
Victoria Wood: and a few others. I think
Victoria Wood: that sounds like a rock and roll band.
jill mcnitt-gray: Jordan in the mind.
Jordan Sturdy: Yeah, I I'm I'm glad we're going by names, because I totally forgot what group number we were. So it was good. I think I was designated to speak. We were cut off right. We're deciding this. But
Jordan Sturdy: we I say, I don't think we got as focused as some of these other groups. But I'm I'm really glad what Kristen was just saying at the end, because what we talked about
Jordan Sturdy: after
Jordan Sturdy: realizing that the instructions for the obstacle course were important was part of that, using it to sort of classify people. Based on how they chose to sort of optimize the course.
Jordan Sturdy: It started because I mentioned that my cat is the same color as the runner on my stairs.
Jordan Sturdy: and so when you have, like an obstacle that you're not aware of. You know you step on it, and then you try to adjust and not kill it, but also not kill yourself by falling down the stairs.
Jordan Sturdy: This introduces a a really interesting control strategy to to your life.
Jordan Sturdy: so so we had a lot of a lot of discussion around. So how do you design an obstacle? Course that maybe you can get an unexpected obstacle?
Jordan Sturdy: And then some of this was, you know you set the obstacle. Course you you let people do it so many times and get some familiarity with it. And then on, you know, whatever 20th time they do it, or something. There's there's something new on the other side that they can't see. And so then they have to make an adjustment after that and you can sort of see how they choose to handle that kinematically, or what what their reaction strategy is.
Jordan Sturdy: and then we? Then we started talking about like, well, you need to have some instructions like you could do it like the 6 min walk test, where it's not necessarily, like, you know, walk as fast as you can, but you know, just walk. See how far you get in 6 min. So it sort of gives the person, the ability to say, well, I don't. I don't want to waste a lot of energy, so I'm not gonna do this as fast as I can but there still is some component of you want to get as far as you can.
Jordan Sturdy: And and so that that was where we started started weeding into these like
Jordan Sturdy: using it to sort of assess. What are people's, you know? Fear avoidance or strategies to to handle an unexpected obstacle? You know. Maybe they've they've changed.
Jordan Sturdy: They've they've had an injury like an acl injury. Where now they have the experience of walking around and randomly, they can't control their knee, and they fall down, and so does that change how they might approach an obstacle.
Jordan Sturdy: So we were talking about leveraging the
Jordan Sturdy: the course, to sort of tease some of these things out
Jordan Sturdy: with with sort of this unexpected
Jordan Sturdy: obstacle idea of leaving it so no balance beams in ours.
jill mcnitt-gray: But I think that brings up an interesting
jill mcnitt-gray: issues adaptation to the challenge with some clear objectives and maybe same thing. Different objectives. What do they solve it? As because that's nice from an experiment point of view, because the same person same day.
jill mcnitt-gray: same task, but with different objectives. So how do they make choices there? But I also really like the unexpected
jill mcnitt-gray: hurdle or obstacle, or a need to adapt because you might get some ideas about control
jill mcnitt-gray: waiting and preferences of what
jill mcnitt-gray: choices are being made in decision making right? And so I think, in the core for modeling is this is a big part of what Christian and Edie are working on, as well as if we know something more about the person and their risk reward.
jill mcnitt-gray: as well as their learning and adaptation to challenges. This is adding a lot more richness. Going back to what Lena talked about is getting to know what the capacities are, but also their decision making what it might be based on. Because if you know these things as part of your warm up to your research project.
jill mcnitt-gray: you can then better understand why the person might be doing what they're doing in the actual task you're trying to study. So I think I talked to Katie about this a little bit is a warm up activity that actually allows you to get a little bit, get to know your subjects or participants a little bit better.
jill mcnitt-gray: Recognizing that it might influence what they do, but at least building that into the experimental design piece
jill mcnitt-gray: any other thoughts, questions, additions from the rest of the band.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Band.
jill mcnitt-gray: It it.
jill mcnitt-gray: Jordan, in my part.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Alright. Should I go ahead and share my screen? John.
Victoria Wood: I think.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah, did we get through everybody?
jill mcnitt-gray: I think one more.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yep.
Hannah Houde(she/her): I think we might be the last group. It was me.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Sorry.
jill mcnitt-gray: In June. No, no, it'll.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, we can't talk.
Hannah Houde(she/her): Yeah. So we all had different, you know, backgrounds. And so we were trying to combine our backgrounds. And so we ended up individually talking about what would be of interest. And so my interest, again, is in Paris sport. So I'm really interested in okay, you know what happens when we make an athlete.
Hannah Houde(she/her): make like what Jill had said, make a choice. What happens to their kinematics? What happens to their pressure in their wheelchair? And then, now let's add, maybe a defensive player. And how does that impact their movement at a ball? All these little aspects go into? How athletes move, and it also goes into
Hannah Houde(she/her): clinical applications, too. So if you know, you have to make a quick reaction. But you don't. Let's say you have Parkinson's and throws your balance off. That can now be, you know, a threat to falling, which kind of goes into our earlier conversation of kinesiophobia so trying to protect your body more or less from injury.
Hannah Houde(she/her): And then, Vanson he was talking about, you know, coming out of the block as a sprinter, and so kind of more or less, the gist was, how do we moneyball movement? If anybody's familiar with moneyball, you know, how can we start to analyze these movement patterns that will predict our highest level of performance, you know. So from a
Hannah Houde(she/her): coach's perspective, like, it's great for them to know your athletes healthy, you know. They're not at risk for acl tear based off of this analysis. Xyz. But they also want to know, you know, what's the percentage for us to be successful on the court. You know. How are we going to? How is this going to lead us to winning a game? How is this going to lead to this
Hannah Houde(she/her): athletes coming in 1st when they come out of the block. So that was more or less our conversations.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think it's a really interesting question, especially in the Paris sports area, and looking at classification of with the goal of making the competition safe and an equal playing ground. I think, in working with some of the para athletes, some of the
jill mcnitt-gray: modifications
jill mcnitt-gray: into their nervous system, and other things may actually lend itself to be a plus rather than a minus in terms of control. And things like that just depends on the task. The person in the role in the, in the sport itself. But there's a lot of discovery in that space, and you also have very motivated participants in that space which makes for
jill mcnitt-gray: co-creating together on what tasks and what activities, and involving the participant because they may know better than you will in terms of what research questions could actually be answered, based on what they know about their capabilities and the current state of their capabilities.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think you also brought in in the chat to about aging and disability as we age and getting up there in numbers for me, it's definitely an issue so welcome to the to the process. We're all going to end up in a adapted or modified state eventually. And I think these are really important as we design the world we we're moving in, you know, for both safety and performance aspects. So it's very rich in that space.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Alright!
jill mcnitt-gray: Do you want to go to the next slide.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think we're yeah. That'd be cool.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): There you go!
jill mcnitt-gray: So I think this is really helpful to
jill mcnitt-gray: talking groups about this. And so for kind of our final breakout room, and it might be kind of a lightning round with. But we've got some really rich conversations here is to think about like something very specific, like hopscotch, and I don't know if you've all played hopscotch. So I listed the rules here where you basically have to, you start still, throw a marker on a square, and then you have to hop through it.
jill mcnitt-gray: but you can't land on the square that has the marker in it, and you go through the whole process. I was also amazed to find out that the world's record was 1 min and 2 seconds. So I'm like, I don't know how they did that, but we're not going for the world record. But
jill mcnitt-gray: think of an activity like this where you're going to hop single leg, hop, double leg, hop a top, and turn at the end. There's a balance issue of picking up the marker and picking it up as you go past. You have to be on one leg and reach down and pick it up. But even just taking a simple course like this Popscotch.
jill mcnitt-gray: what all do you think you might learn by the series of tasks that you might put together in a obstacle course because you talked, and how that might give a
jill mcnitt-gray: better picture of your participants. Capacities like you're saying their personalities, the risk reward, the evidence of previous experience and such like that. So in our next breakout group, maybe we could talk specifically about
jill mcnitt-gray: how you would like to modify the Mc Hopscotch court and or tasks and or objectives, and see if we can maybe try something like this out. So we'll go back to breakout groups and talk about it, and then report back.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): And maybe 10 min or 8.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah, yeah.
Victoria Wood: Alright! These will be quick. I'll send you guys back to your breakout rooms. Now.
jill mcnitt-gray: We want to keep the discussion going, so no worries.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay. It's gonna be quick.
Victoria Wood: Oh.
Victoria Wood: and for some reason you weren't assigned back to one.
Hannah Houde(she/her): Might have been my June had to leave, so I don't know if Vincent is here, so that might be why.
Victoria Wood: Yes, Vincent's still there. Let me assign you to that room, too. Right?
Victoria Wood: This is so fun for me to like hear about. So my work was in my Phd. Work was in like orientation, perception following gravity transitions, and so we did a lot of like
Victoria Wood: balance and movement tasks to assess, but they were all very constrained for safety purposes.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, of course.
Victoria Wood: Oriented. So we did a lot of like, you know, eyes closed, tandem.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Right.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Nobody could make it more than like 2 steps. So it's like these are
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): a lot of the balance beam stuff in different genres of dance and humans with different yeah, I, it's interesting because I like the balance beam task. But I would like to to be something that we could do with people with different abilities as well.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): So. But we have some ideas. It's good. It's interesting to see where people are.
Victoria Wood: That makes sense.
Victoria Wood: Now, is your plan for these like to
Victoria Wood: like? Where are you gonna set these up with participants and things.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I mean, the idea would be that we could do it. So I work with people different abilities. Up in mammoth lakes doing different summer tasks like mountain biking paddle, boarding, climbing things like that. And so it would, you know, ideally, we'd like to be able to do it in all bodies, so we might have to modify what that looks like. But the idea would be, we 1st try to run it at Uci. But we will see. Getting permission to use a drone is
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): little tricky.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, like noise.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): No more. Yeah, it's just privacy. It's really interesting in danger, like, whatever the drone, you know. But but wanna promise that's in our group. She's actually a dance major and aerospace engineer major as well. And she has, like level flight level 4 drone abilities. So I think we're going to be okay. But it's just navigating, like.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): you know, and I think in most places you probably could do it until you get caught kind of moment. And then that's but not at Uci. We can't do that. But everywhere else we're probably just waiting until we get trouble.
Victoria Wood: Nice.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. But just pairing the data right now is what we're you know of. A big focus is figuring out how to get the 2D. And the drone data together.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, yeah, that'll be tricky. But very great data.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah. And if we have to do it separately, that's okay, too. But yeah, alright, probably
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): 4 more minutes, maybe.
Victoria Wood: Yeah, give him like a 2 min warning and then close it. So they have the extra.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): You know.
Victoria Wood: It's been like 5 min for them already. Right? Yeah, we. I think we started at 1 12.
Victoria Wood: Alright. I'll go ahead and close the rooms.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): So, being mindful of time, I think we should jump right into the discussion.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yep.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Anyone want to start?
jill mcnitt-gray: Let's do the same order just to keep us going.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yep. Exactly. Go ahead.
jill mcnitt-gray: Emily? Or whoever is it?
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yep.
Emily Smith: I may have been digressing, and not actually ask answering the question that was asked, but, we talked about just generally the importance of game or play in in these tasks that we're giving so to to specifically in 2 different directions, like, when you're playing a game, you're kind of tricking your brain into changing your focus and
Emily Smith: in my experience that leads to better performance. But
Emily Smith: that whereas, like, for example, Kristen's latter task, like you can focus on the task itself. If we, in a game like hopscotch, you may be executing some of those exact same tasks. But in the context of a game your your outcomes may be very different.
Emily Smith: And then the other thing we talked about also was another way to kind of trick the brain a little bit, and to observe different performance
Emily Smith: is, we'll tell people they're getting a trial run when they're not actually getting a trial run like, how so? Someone like Kristen or me, who are maybe a little bit hyper competitive. If you give them a task, they're going to do it at 110. But if I tell you, okay, this is a trial run. It doesn't count. How do you approach that? And what does that tell us about the strategies you choose, and about how you learn.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay, excellent.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I like that. Approach.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Next group.
Victoria Wood: Think we had the Usc. Team.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, I like that idea.
Victoria Wood: Are you still here.
James Finley: Yes, we're still here. We're just deciding who's going to speak up.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Oh, oh, you didn't decide who the reporter was going to be.
James Finley: No, we didn't hourly.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Okay.
James Finley: Well, I I can. My. My interpretation of the instructions was an idea. Around
James Finley: again, how do you introduce the different the task, or how these different tasks are introduced, could provide some insight into learning capacity. So individuals capacity to acquire a new skill. Some will. After a couple of trial runs, will be.
James Finley: be able to produce something highly accurate. Say versus someone who takes more time, and that's another dimension of capacity and the ability to acquire a new skill or refine a new skill.
jill mcnitt-gray: So is that capturing some of the learning aspects of this, too. Right? Yeah.
James Finley: Yeah, about that with dancers practicing things at quarter time or half time, or double time.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): All right. Next group.
Kristen Jakubowski: I think that's our group. And I think it'll surprise no one, especially Emily, at this point that I got hyper focused on the world, the world record of Popscotch, and how they achieved it.
Kristen Jakubowski: But to me like it, it came down to our discussion, largely focused on a question of like the person's overall strategy, and that may also be indicative of their confidence in the task and their confidence, their ability.
Kristen Jakubowski: in sort of 2 different aspects of it of did they decide to go for the furthest box. First? st Did they decide to go for a closer box earlier on not only in their sort of confidence in their throwing ability, but also, as we think about fatigue. If you have to hit all of the boxes like what overall strategy is the person using to accomplish the task as fast as possible? And how does that strategy differ from person to person?
jill mcnitt-gray: There might be a link there between
jill mcnitt-gray: what they know of themselves. Right? That's kind of the expression there, very cool.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Excellent is it time for the band yet.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yes.
Jordan Sturdy: The it's a it's a funk metal band.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Play off of your last name to you a little bit.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, especially what we're talking about. Balance dirty, anyway. Go ahead.
Jordan Sturdy: So yeah, I actually, I had to look up the rules for offscotch while the rest of my band was discussing things because I didn't actually know there were rules.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
Jordan Sturdy: So this is, this is cool we. We sort of sort of what we settle on was
Jordan Sturdy: The idea of like having somebody do it, and getting like getting their steady state like seeing how they do it in repetition. And a couple of things you can get from, that is.
Jordan Sturdy: when they have the opportunity. Sort of to switch which foot like which single leg foot they're hopping on. Do they switch? Or do they always go back to the same like dominant foot, or something like that, to hop on
Jordan Sturdy: or do they switch, maybe to like, you know, spread out the the fatigue onto both legs.
Jordan Sturdy: and so, you know, you sort of you can. You can get this assess some sort of steady state, and from that you can perturb it, either by forcing them to like alternate feet when they hit the double squares, or to always hop on their other foot, or to like, you know, change where change which square they're skipping is in after they've gotten like sort of used to a certain pattern.
Jordan Sturdy: You know, getting getting at some of those like learning aspects. How do you handle this like
Jordan Sturdy: forcing you to do something you're not used to? How how does that incur more errors, or like in increase the time it takes you to do the task.
Victoria Wood: Alright great! And then we have one last group.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think, Hannah, that was your group somewhere.
Vanson Vu: Yeah, yeah, Hannah. And I was last group. But we yeah, our discussion was mostly focused on like balance because of just how much of like a role it plays in the game. So we discussed how like you could put like a force plate on the layout of the
Vanson Vu: Popscotch board on the ground, and then kind of analyze where, like the pressure of the foot, is like landing and like holding when people are trying to find their balance, and then also like hop to the next square, and then just using that to like.
Vanson Vu: like or like, comparing that with like success and performance, to see like.
Vanson Vu: where is the most optimal, like place on the foot to kind of land from, and then hop from to like, optimize the success on the task.
jill mcnitt-gray: Yeah. So the the challenge on these pop up arenas is to try to measure what we can right? Whether it's sensors or these Timestamps, synchronized ipads, or the drone above, or these kind of things. And
jill mcnitt-gray: one of the things we've learned in this came actually from wheelchair Ireland is use the tree principles which you guys are all playing with, which is T for technique. You know how you need to do the tasks, whether it's on your dominant non-dominant, those kind of things changing up the rules, changing the equipment or changing the environment. You know things like, okay, let's do hopscotch. But let's put a sheet over top where you can't touch the sheet
jill mcnitt-gray: right? So now, are you going to hop? But yet not touch the sheet. Those kind of things right? So there's ways you can constrain
jill mcnitt-gray: with or require the adaptation you're searching for by switching up.
jill mcnitt-gray: the intention, the technique, the rules, the equipment and the environment. And so that that ends up being a really nice framework to think about what all you could learn with same tasks, but just kind of changing
jill mcnitt-gray: the instructions right or the constraints. So so I hopefully, we've gotten you guys thinking, I know we have 1 min left. So this is perfect. I'm glad we had time together and to meet everybody, especially as we're starting our Summer Institute projects.
jill mcnitt-gray: But thank you. We will ask people to add to our video library of ideas. So you now have a low tech way of actually collecting some of the movements that you come up with, so we may tap into you as the summer goes on, and we have a Google drive in the Pop up arena where you can put some of your ideas. So we hope that you'll contribute in that way.
jill mcnitt-gray: I think there's 1 more QR code that we need to share for
jill mcnitt-gray: evaluating or giving feedback on the workshop. But we really appreciate you guys thinking flexibly today and coming up with some really good ideas for our group to consider. So we look forward to co-creating with you in the future.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Boom.
jill mcnitt-gray: And I. You probably need to put the here you go the link into the chat again.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, working on it.
jill mcnitt-gray: Thank you. Everybody have a great day, and let us know what you come up with your hopscotch. Course.
Emily Smith: Thank you.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Or any other task.
jill mcnitt-gray: That's right.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): I've thought about some reaching ones while we're doing here. We go.
jill mcnitt-gray: There's the link.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah.
jill mcnitt-gray: Thank you. Victoria.
Kelli Sharp (she/her/hers): Yeah, thank you. I will share that folder where you want people to upload videos. The Pdf, with the.
Victoria Wood: Low cost video setup again.
Victoria Wood: Thank you so much. Of course.
jill mcnitt-gray: Alright! Take care! Bye.
Victoria Wood: Bye, everyone.